Hello, everyone, and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听 EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
My name is Catherine, and today we've got one more episode in our series about interview
我是 Catherine，今天我们带来的是面试技巧系列中的又一集。
skills.
技巧。
This is an elementary level series, and we're here today to talk about things that you might
这是一个初级水平的系列，今天我们要讨论的是你可能不太擅长的事情。
not be very good at.
不擅长的事情。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about weaknesses, and that is our word for vocabulary preview.
今天我们要谈谈弱点，这也是我们词汇预览中的单词。
So let's take a look at it now.
那我们现在就来看看吧。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so what is a weakness?
好的，那么什么是弱点？
A weakness is a thing or an activity or something that you're just not very good at or something
弱点是指你不擅长的事情、活动，或者你认为可以改进的地方。
that you think you can improve.
可以改进的地方。
Okay, so obviously no one is perfect, and like we saw in the previous lesson, we had
好的，显然没有人是完美的，就像我们在上一课中看到的，我们有很多关于自己的优点、关键优势，现在我们要谈谈。
a lot of good things about ourselves, key strengths, and now we're going to talk about
关键优势，现在我们要谈谈。
our weaknesses.
我们的弱点。
Maybe you're a little bit lazy.
也许你有点懒。
That might be a weakness.
那可能是一个弱点。
That's right.
没错。
A weakness is the opposite of strength, and that is the topic today, so let's take a listen
弱点是优势的反义词，这就是今天的主题，所以让我们来听听。
to today's dialogue.
今天的对话。
Okay, Rebecca.
好的，Rebecca。
Well I think you've given me a clear impression of your positive qualities, but let's talk
嗯，我想你已经让我清楚了解了你的优点，但让我们谈谈。
a little bit about your weaknesses.
谈谈你的弱点。
Okay.
好的。
Well it's always more difficult to describe them, isn't it?
嗯，描述它们总是更难，不是吗？
Definitely, but if you had to pinpoint one weakness, what would it be?
确实，但如果你必须指出一个弱点，那会是什么？
Well as I mentioned before, I do tend to get frustrated if I don't see progress in my work
嗯，正如我之前提到的，如果我在工作或职业中看不到进展，我确实会感到沮丧。
or career.
或职业。
I suppose I'm quite a restless character.
我想我是一个相当不安分的人。
My father always taught me to be a high achiever, so...
我父亲总是教导我要成为高成就者，所以……
So would you say if things don't go your way at work, it could easily get you down?
那么你会说，如果工作中事情不顺利，很容易让你沮丧吗？
Well in a way, yes, but I must say that even if I'm not completely happy in my work, I
嗯，在某种程度上是的，但我必须说，即使我对工作不完全满意，我。
always give 110%.
总是付出110%的努力。
I would never shirk my responsibilities.
我从不逃避责任。
I suppose sometimes I expect too much too soon.
我想有时候我期望太多太快了。
Well you know journalism is a highly competitive world, so you do need to keep pushing yourself,
嗯，你知道新闻业是一个竞争激烈的世界，所以你需要不断推动自己，
it's true.
这是真的。
Okay, well let's move on to talk about the job position here, shall we?
好的，那我们继续谈谈这个职位吧，好吗？
Yes, please.
好的，请。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously, Rebecca did a very good job at talking about her weaknesses in a very
显然，Rebecca 在以一种非常积极的方式谈论她的弱点方面做得很好。
positive way.
积极的方式。
So before we get into analyzing that, why don't we take a look at a couple of words
在我们分析之前，不如先看看她在“语言小贴士”中用到的一些词。
she used on Language Takeaway.
她用到的一些词。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
One of the first words that Mr. Parsons used was a clear impression, so impression.
Parsons 先生用的第一个词是“清晰的印象”，所以是印象。
Alright so I think this is a very common word when people talk about first impressions or
好的，我认为这是一个很常见的词，当人们谈论第一印象或。
I get the impression.
我得到印象时。
So what is an impression?
那么什么是印象？
Well an impression is like an idea or a feeling.
嗯，印象就像一种想法或感觉。
So I can have an impression about something, it means that I don't necessarily understand
所以我可以对某事有印象，这意味着我不一定非常理解。
it really well or I don't have experience with it, but it's an idea that I have about
它或对它没有经验，但这是我关于某事的一个想法。
something.
一个想法。
That's right, so for example, maybe you meet somebody new and you say I get the impression
没错，比如，你可能遇到一个新朋友，然后你说我得到印象。
that he is a liar.
他是个骗子。
But maybe then you get to know him and he's not.
但也许后来你了解他，发现他不是。
So this is your idea about something or the way you feel about something.
所以这是你对某事的想法或感觉。
So in this case, Mr. Parsons has a clear impression of her positive qualities.
所以在这种情况下，Parsons 先生对她的优点有清晰的印象。
That means that he has an idea or an understanding of the things that Rebecca is good at, but
这意味着他对 Rebecca 擅长的事情有一个想法或理解，但。
he wants to know more about her weaknesses.
他想了解更多关于她的弱点。
That's right and Mr. Parsons asked her to try and pinpoint one of her weaknesses.
没错，Parsons 先生让她试着指出她的一个弱点。
So this word to pinpoint.
所以这个词是“指出”。
This is a great word, I'm not really sure where it comes from in English, but I think
这是一个很好的词，我不太确定它在英语中来自哪里，但我认为。
it's very visual, you can see what the word means.
它非常形象，你能看出这个词的意思。
Pinpoint means to locate or identify or really be specific about something.
“指出”意味着定位、识别或非常具体地说明某事。
That's right, so maybe if you go to the doctor and you say that your back hurts, the doctor
没错，比如，如果你去看医生，说你的背疼，医生。
might ask you to try and pinpoint where on your back you have the pain.
可能会让你试着指出背上哪里疼。
That's right, so it's a way to be specific or very exact about something.
没错，所以这是一种具体或精确说明某事的方式。
Okay, so if she had to pinpoint something, she said, well, I do get a little bit frustrated.
好的，所以如果她必须指出一点，她说，嗯，我确实会有点沮丧。
Okay, so frustrated is a way you feel.
好的，所以“沮丧”是一种感觉。
I feel frustrated, he is frustrated.
我感到沮丧，他感到沮丧。
It's basically a feeling that you get when you have to do something, but you don't think
基本上，当你必须做某事但你认为自己做不到，或者某事让你烦恼时，你就会感到沮丧。
you can do it or maybe something annoys you and you get frustrated.
你就会感到沮丧。
For example, when people tap like this and I'm working, I get frustrated because it's
比如，当我在工作时有人这样敲桌子，我会感到沮丧，因为那是。
a distraction.
一种干扰。
Okay, so everyone has different things that frustrate them.
好的，所以每个人都有不同的事情让他们沮丧。
Now if we take a look at this word, it is actually an adjective and we usually use it,
现在如果我们看看这个词，它实际上是一个形容词，我们通常用它。
you get frustrated or as you said, you feel frustrated.
你变得沮丧，或者像你说的，你感到沮丧。
So remember, it may look like a verb, but it's actually an adjective that ends in ed,
所以记住，它可能看起来像动词，但实际上是一个以 ed 结尾的形容词。
frustrated, to get frustrated.
感到沮丧，变得沮丧。
He got frustrated or we feel very frustrated.
他变得沮丧，或者我们感到非常沮丧。
Okay, and well, apart from being frustrated, she also said that she is a restless character.
好的，除了感到沮丧，她还说她是个不安分的人。
Okay, so someone is restless if they don't like to stay in one place all the time.
好的，所以如果一个人不喜欢一直待在同一个地方，那就是不安分。
That means someone who wants to move around or to go places or to travel or to see new
这意味着一个人想要四处走动、去不同的地方、旅行或见识新
things is restless.
事物，就是不安分。
That's right.
没错。
So she has a restless character, that means she likes to move around.
所以她性格不安分，这意味着她喜欢四处走动。
She doesn't like to stand still in one place.
她不喜欢一直待在同一个地方。
Maybe she gets bored very easily.
也许她很容易感到无聊。
Okay, so that's somebody that would be restless.
好的，那就是不安分的人。
But moving on, she also said that she doesn't like to shirk her responsibilities.
但继续说，她还说她不喜欢逃避责任。
Okay, you often hear these words go together.
好的，你经常听到这些词一起出现。
So responsibilities are things that we need to do, right?
所以责任是我们需要做的事情，对吧？
Things that other people expect us to do, to shirk a responsibility means to not do
别人期望我们做的事情，逃避责任意味着不做
something that you're supposed to do.
你应该做的事情。
It means to avoid responsibility or to push it away.
这意味着避免责任或推卸责任。
Okay, so it's a verb, to shirk your responsibilities.
好的，所以它是一个动词，逃避你的责任。
You shouldn't shirk your responsibilities.
你不应该逃避你的责任。
That's right.
没错。
Alright, so a lot of interesting key words there.
好的，那里有很多有趣的关键词。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
我们为什么不重新听一遍对话，然后回来进行流利度训练。
Okay Rebecca, well I think you've given me a clear impression of your positive qualities,
好的，Rebecca，我想你已经清楚地让我看到了你的优点，
but let's talk a little bit about your weaknesses.
但我们来谈谈你的缺点吧。
Okay, well it's always more difficult to describe them, isn't it?
好的，描述缺点总是更难，不是吗？
Definitely, but if you had to pinpoint one weakness, what would it be?
确实，但如果你必须指出一个缺点，那会是什么？
Well as I mentioned before, I do tend to get frustrated if I don't see progress in my
嗯，就像我之前提到的，如果我在工作或职业中看不到进展，
work or career.
我确实容易感到沮丧。
I suppose I'm quite a restless character.
我想我是个相当不安分的人。
My father always taught me to be a high achiever, so...
我父亲总是教导我要成为高成就者，所以……
So would you say if things don't go your way at work, it could easily get you down?
那么你会说，如果工作中事情不顺利，很容易让你情绪低落吗？
Well, in a way, yes.
嗯，在某种程度上，是的。
But I must say that even if I'm not completely happy in my work, I always give 110%.
但我必须说，即使我对工作不完全满意，我总是付出110%的努力。
I would never shirk my responsibilities.
我从不逃避我的责任。
I suppose sometimes I expect too much too soon.
我想有时候我期望太多、太快了。
Well, you know journalism is a highly competitive world, so you do need to keep pushing yourself,
嗯，你知道新闻业是一个竞争激烈的世界，所以你需要不断推动自己，
it's true.
这是真的。
Okay, well let's move on to talk about the job position here, shall we?
好的，那我们继续谈谈这里的职位，好吗？
Yes please.
好的，请。
So we've picked out three key phrases for you on Fluency Builder.
我们在流利度训练中为你挑选了三个关键短语。
Let's take a look at those now.
我们现在来看看这些。
Starting with Mr. Parson saying, so would you say if things don't go your way at work,
从Parson先生说的开始：那么你会说，如果工作中事情不顺利，
it could easily get you down?
很容易让你情绪低落吗？
Two great phrases there.
那里有两个很好的短语。
That's right.
没错。
So the first phrase, if things don't go your way.
所以第一个短语：如果事情不顺利。
So this is kind of a funny phrase when you think about it because they go your way like
这其实是个有点有趣的短语，因为“go your way”像是
to me or what is my way.
朝我这边或我的方向。
This basically means if things do not happen in a way that makes you happy or in a way
这基本上意味着事情没有以让你开心或
that you expect.
你期望的方式发生。
Okay, so we could say he lost his job, he couldn't pay his bills, things just didn't
好的，所以我们可以说：他丢了工作，付不起账单，事情就是
go his way.
不顺利。
That's right.
没错。
So things are not happening as he planned or as he expected.
所以事情没有按他计划或期望的那样发生。
You can also say the opposite.
你也可以说相反的情况。
So he won the lottery and he also met a really beautiful girl who wanted to be his girlfriend.
所以他中了彩票，还遇到了一个想当他女朋友的漂亮女孩。
Things were going his way.
事情很顺利。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So if things are going your way, it's good.
所以如果事情顺利，那就是好事。
If things aren't going your way, then it's bad.
如果事情不顺利，那就是坏事。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, and so if things aren't going Rebecca's way, does that mean that it could easily get
好的，那么如果事情对Rebecca不顺利，这是否意味着很容易让她
her down?
情绪低落？
Okay, so to get you down or to get someone down means to make you sad, upset or frustrated
好的，所以“get you down”或“get someone down”意味着让你伤心、难过或沮丧，
like that where we just heard.
就像我们刚才听到的那样。
So you could ask someone like, Marco, what gets you down?
所以你可以问某人，比如：Marco，什么会让你情绪低落？
Rainy days.
下雨天。
That's a good one.
这是个好例子。
Yeah, rainy days get me down too.
是啊，下雨天也会让我情绪低落。
So it's kind of a way of saying what makes you sad or depressed or what makes you unhappy.
所以这是一种表达什么让你伤心、抑郁或不开心的方式。
Or in this case, if something doesn't happen as you planned it, if it doesn't go your way,
或者在这个例子中，如果事情没有按你计划的那样发生，如果不顺利，
does that make you sad?
那会让你难过吗？
Does that get you down?
那会让你情绪低落吗？
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a very good question there.
所以那是个很好的问题。
And she responded that kind of, yeah, that does happen, but she always tries to give
她回答说，某种程度上，是的，确实会发生，但她总是努力付出
110%.
110%的努力。
Okay, so this is a really funny phrase because you think I can give everything I have.
好的，这真是个有趣的短语，因为你会想我可以付出我所有的一切。
I can work really hard and that's 100%.
我可以非常努力地工作，那是100%。
But we say 110% means you do more than you can.
但我们说110%意味着你做得比你能做的更多。
It's like pushing yourself more than is possible.
这就像是在逼自己超越极限。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a very common phrase in sports and business.
所以这在体育和商业中是一个非常常见的短语。
People are saying, for example, I always remember my coach saying, I want you guys to give me
人们常说，比如，我一直记得我的教练说，我要你们在场上给我
110% out there.
110% 的努力。
That means I really want you to try very hard to do as much as possible.
这意味着我真的希望你们尽力做到最好。
Even more than your best, more than you think you can do.
甚至超越你的最佳状态，超越你认为自己能做到的。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So again, it refers to the effort that you put into something.
所以，它指的是你投入某件事的努力。
It can be in business, sports, anything.
可以是商业、体育，任何领域。
And she's basically saying, I always do more than my best.
而她基本上是在说，我总是做得比最好还要好。
I do as much as humanly possible.
我尽人类所能做到的最大努力。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so a lot of great stuff there from Rebecca.
好的，Rebecca 说了很多很棒的内容。
Why don't we listen to her one last time and we'll be back in a bit.
我们最后再听一次她的话，然后稍后再回来。
Okay, Rebecca.
好的，Rebecca。
Well I think you've given me a clear impression of your positive qualities.
嗯，我想你已经让我清楚地看到了你的优点。
But let's talk a little bit about your weaknesses.
但让我们谈谈你的缺点吧。
Okay.
好的。
Well it's always more difficult to describe them, isn't it?
嗯，描述它们总是更难，不是吗？
Definitely.
确实。
But if you had to pinpoint one weakness, what would it be?
但如果你必须指出一个缺点，那会是什么？
Well as I mentioned before, I do tend to get frustrated if I don't see progress in my work
嗯，就像我之前提到的，如果我在工作或职业上看不到进展，我确实容易感到沮丧。
or career.
或职业。
I suppose I'm quite a restless character.
我想我是一个相当不安分的人。
My father always taught me to be a high achiever, so...
我父亲总是教导我要成为高成就者，所以……
So would you say if things don't go your way at work, it could easily get you down?
那么你会说，如果工作不顺心，很容易让你情绪低落吗？
Well in a way, yes.
嗯，在某种程度上，是的。
But I must say that even if I'm not completely happy in my work, I always give 110%.
但我必须说，即使我对工作不完全满意，我总是付出110%的努力。
I would never shirk my responsibilities.
我绝不会逃避责任。
I suppose sometimes I expect too much too soon.
我想有时候我期望太多、太快了。
Well you know journalism is a highly competitive world, so you do need to keep pushing yourself,
嗯，你知道新闻业是一个竞争非常激烈的领域，所以你需要不断鞭策自己，
it's true.
这是真的。
Okay, well let's move on to talk about the job position here, shall we?
好的，那我们继续谈谈这个职位吧，好吗？
Yes, please.
好的，请。
Alright, so talking about weaknesses, I think one of the common mistakes when people talk
好的，说到缺点，我认为人们谈论缺点时常见的错误之一就是说自己工作太努力。
about weaknesses is they say they work too much.
而且每个人都说你在面试中绝不应该这么说。
And everyone says you should never say that in an interview.
是的，我认为这是一种不好的自我描述方式，因为老板或雇主真的想听到一个真实的缺点。
Yeah, I think it's a bad way to talk about yourself because a boss or an employer really
而“我工作太努力”是一种说“我没有缺点”的方式。
wants to hear a real weakness.
我实际上真的非常完美。
And I work too hard is a way of saying, I have no weaknesses.
我只是觉得这是一个懒惰的回答。
I'm actually really, really perfect.
所以也许你应该避免说“我工作太努力”，而是真正专注于那些你需要改进的事情。
I just think it's a lazy answer.
然后我认为关键是说，我知道这是我难以应对的事情，我知道这是一个缺点，我正在努力改进。
So maybe you should avoid saying I work too hard and really focus on things that you do
是的，我记得在我参加的一些面试中，我常见的回答是，有时候我经常迟到，不太守时。
have to work on.
但你知道，这是一个真实的缺点，可能看起来很难，但你可以稍微扭转一下，说，是的，我有时不太守时，但我会努力弥补，比如在办公室多待一会儿，或者有时我试着早起一点，准时到达。
And then I think the key is to say that I know this is something that I have a hard
我不知道，类似这样的。
time with, I know this is a weakness and I'm trying to improve it.
然后我认为关键是说，我知道这是我难以应对的事情，我知道这是一个缺点，我正在努力改进。
Yeah, I remember in some of the interviews I've had, I think my common answer was sometimes
是的，我记得在我参加的一些面试中，我常见的回答是，有时候我经常迟到，不太守时。
I'm very late, I'm not very punctual.
但你知道，这是一个真实的缺点，可能看起来很难，但你可以稍微扭转一下，说，是的，我有时不太守时，但我会努力弥补，比如在办公室多待一会儿，或者有时我试着早起一点，准时到达。
But you know, it's a real weakness and it may seem like difficult, but then you give
我不知道，类似这样的。
it a little spin by saying, yeah, I'm sometimes not very punctual, but then I try to make
但你知道，这是一个真实的缺点，可能看起来很难，但你可以稍微扭转一下，说，是的，我有时不太守时，但我会努力弥补，比如在办公室多待一会儿，或者有时我试着早起一点，准时到达。
up for it, maybe staying more time at the office, or sometimes I try to wake up a little
我不知道，类似这样的。
bit earlier and make it on time.
I don't know, something like that.
我不知道，类似这样的。
Right.
对。
So the key there is just to show that you know it's a problem and that you're trying
所以关键是要表明你知道这是一个问题，并且你在努力改进。
to work on it.
是的。
Yeah.
So this is actually the hardest part for me of an interview, talking about yourself in
所以这实际上是我在面试中最难的部分，以负面的方式谈论自己，因为显然你想得到这份工作。
a negative way, because obviously you want to get the job.
所以你要确保雇主对你有好的印象，但这很难。
So you want to make sure that the employer has a good idea of yourself, but it's hard.
我认为这对每个人来说都是最难的部分。
I think it's the hardest part for everyone.
我认为这不只是你一个人这样。
I don't think it's just you.
是的，这很难。
Yeah, it's hard.
So this is an interesting topic.
所以这是一个有趣的话题。
Why don't you practice and come to our website EnglishPod.com and on our comment section,
你为什么不练习一下，然后来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在我们的评论区，
why don't you tell us what your weaknesses are?
告诉我们你的缺点是什么？
That's right.
没错。
We hope to hear from you.
我们期待听到你的消息。
Of course, you can also share with us your strengths on our lesson about strengths.
当然，你也可以在我们的优点课程上分享你的优点。
But in this one, I recommend everyone practice this because it will come up at some point
但在这节课中，我建议大家练习这个，因为它迟早会出现，提前练习是好的。
and it's good to get the practice in.
所以 EnglishPod.com，我们希望能看到你。
So EnglishPod.com, we hope to see you there.
好的，各位。
All right, guys.
再见。
Bye.
Bye山本太一.
再见，山本太一。